Finding Aid for Julio Perazza visual materials, 1970s and 1984-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Julio Perazza visual materials 1970s and 1984-1986
Perazza, Julio
0.2 linear feet
2009180 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Ana Luisa Cardona (donor no. 10213 ) in June 2009.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Julio Perazza was born in San Juan, Puerto Rico on August 29, 1943. After graduating from Western High School in Detroit, he studied at various places, including Highland Park Community College. He eventually completed his B.F.A. in photography at the University of Michigan (1975) and his M.F.A. in photography from Eastern Michigan University.
He worked for a time at Great Lakes Steel, and later toured as a performer and photographer with the musical performing arts company "Up with People". Perazza devoted his life to photography, both as an artist and as a teacher. The subjects of his photographs were African-Americans in Detroit, Chicanos in Michigan, and life in his homeland of Puerto Rico. His artwork has been exhibited throughout Michigan and around California, Texas, Washington, D.C. and Chicago. He died July 28, 1998.
The Julio Perazza collection consists of photograph negatives taken during the period of 1984-1986. The images relate mainly to the Hispanic community of Detroit, particularly of activities at Casa de Unidad. These include photographs of various classes (dance, photography, etc.) and of social events sponsored by this Hispanic organization. The collection also includes a motion picture created by Latino students at the University of Michigan in the early 1970s intended as a recruiting tool to encourage individuals to apply for admission.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Casa de Unidad (Detroit, Mich.); Detroit (Mich.); Hispanic Americans--Education--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Hispanic Americans--Michigan--Detroit.; Perazza, Julio.; Photography--Michigan--Detroit.; Students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students.
Genre Terms:
Motion pictures.; Photographs.
- Negatives
  - June-September 1984
    - Baker's Keyboard Lounge, June 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ann Arbor Art Fair Street Shoot and Detroit Hispanic Festival, July 1984 (Box 1)
    - Latin American Festival, July 1984 (Box 1)
    - Amigo Band at Chene Park, August 1984 (Box 1)
    - La Casa Detroit Hispanic Salsa Band, August 1984 (Box 1)
    - La Casa George Vargas Donating his Art Drawing, August 1984 (Box 1)
    - New York Salsa Band Leader Fountain Play, August 1984 (Box 1)
    - Ozzie's Birthday Surprise Party, September 30-31, 1984 (Box 1)
  - March-May 1985
    - Casa de Unidad Creative Writing Class, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Casa de Unidad Dance Class, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Casa de Unidad Graphics-Other, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Casa de Unidad Photo Class, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Funeral at St. Anne Church 1, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Funeral at St. Anne Church 2, March 1985 (Box 1)
    - Bread/Puppet 1, April 1985 ? (Box 1)
    - Bread/Puppet 2, April 1985 ? (Box 1)
    - Arab and Hispanic Dinner, May 1985 (Box 1)
    - Arab/Hispanic Dinner, May 1985 (Box 1)
    - Clark Park-First Time with Photo Class, May 1985 (Box 1)
  - October-December 1985
    - Devil's Night, October 1985 Christmas, November 1985 Carmen/Mark, November 1985 (Box 1)
    - S.W.A.P. Wear Red Ribbon, November 1985 (Box 1)
    - S.W.A.P. Ribbon Sign on Casa Door, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Flor y Canto de Navidad B, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Flor y Canto de Navidad C, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Flor y Canto de Navidad D, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Front Room Gallery, Julio Perazza's Photos 1, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Front Room Gallery, Julio Perazza's Photos 2, December 1985 (Box 1)
    - Tree Trimming Party A, December 1985 (Box 1)
  - May 1986
    - Theaters A, May 1986 (Box 1)
    - Theaters B, May 1986 (Box 1)
    - Theaters C, May 1986 (Box 1)
    - Theaters D, May 1986 (Box 1)
- Motion picture
  - Motion picture created by Latino students at the University of Michigan in the early 1970s (Box 1)